Chair GPD5 is a huge deal and here's
why. So GPT5 is the biggest release
since the creation of Chad GPT which was
back in 2022. OpenAI says that GPT5 is
like having a team of PhD experts in
your pocket. So in this video I'll teach
you everything you need to know about
GPD5. Now pay attention because GPD5 is
a big deal. Personally I spent over two
years waiting for this model. In the
meantime, I interviewed dozens of AI
experts, made hundreds of videos about
AI, and spent thousands of hours with
tools like CH GBT. So, if you want to
know how to use GPT5 better than 99% of
people, watch until the end. So, this is
what CH GPT looks like right now. And in
the top left, you can see the three main
options: GPD5, GBD5 thinking, and GBD5
Pro. This one costs $200 a month. So,
later in the video, I'll show you what
this beast of a model can do. But first,
let me show you the normal CH GBT with
this prompt. Generate a visual book that
will showcase the fundamental concepts
needed to understand AI and ML. So,
let's send this. Now, while CHGBT is
running, you must understand the
automatic router. CHGBD5s comes with a
built-in model router that automatically
decides which model or LLM it should
use. For simpler requests, you'll get a
quick answer from one of the faster
models. For more complex questions,
however, CHGP will route to more
powerful version such as thinking mode
at the top. But there is a major problem
with this. OpenAI tries to hide it, but
there is only a 32K context window
inside of JIGBT. Now, you might be
thinking, "Okay, David, but why this is
a problem?" The reason is GBT5 can
actually take up to 400,000 tokens of
context. So, OpenAI isn't giving you the
full capacity of the model. This is a
major problem if you want to paste in
books, large PDFs, documents, or if you
just want to chat for a long time. Now,
luckily, there's a simple solution, and
that is using GPD5 inside of Veectal.AI
AI because in Vectal you can use GPD5
with the full 400,000 context window and
the best part is you can try it
completely for free. Just go to
vectal.ai and sign up. Chbet was running
for a few minutes now. This is a
complete hit to companies like lovable,
bold, replet agent because you can build
full web apps inside of CIGBT. Now this
is one of the biggest updates to CIGBD5
that not many people are talking about
actually. There is our app right here.
Look at this. Wow. We have a nice visual
examples. So let's see. Use the arrows
or left to right key to flip between
pages. So look at these illustrations,
right? Boom. This is all customcoded
that GPD5 created. Wow, this is nice.
Look at this very nice visualizations.
Imagine if you had to make a
presentation on this topic. How long
would it take you to create these graphs
and charts? Certainly longer than
sending one prompt CH GBD5. That's for
sure. All right, so now let me go to the
top left, click on new chat, and let me
show you the full power of Chad GBD Pro.
the biggest model OpenAI has to offer.
So, here's the prompt I prepared. Build
a full stack web app in canvas that
shows multiple 3D geometric objects with
several sliders allowing you to change
the quantity and scale of those objects.
So, this is not just a simple book. This
will be an interactive 3D web app that
uh hopefully JBD can make work. We'll
see. Now, while it's cooking that up,
let's jump into few pro tips I observed
from many many hours of testing. Number
one, you should always try to use GBD5
thinking and not the default GBD5,
right? The problem is if we look at this
uh benchmark which is from artificial
analysis you can see that GBD5 minimal
thanks to the router can default to this
model which only performs at 44. This is
very bad. So if you select GBT5 thinking
you will get the medium model which
performs at 68 on this benchmark which
is close to one of the best in the
world. Now if you paid attention to my
first prompt you noticed it included the
words think hard. And this isn't just
some prompt engineering trick. This
actually directly impacts how often the
thinking mode gets triggered in the
model router. Also use the new study
mode for learning anything. This is very
OP. It's by far the fastest way to learn
any new concept. Now to activate study
mode, just click on this plus icon
before it prompt and select study and
learn. This will turn CHBD into being
your personal tutor. Oh, and by the way,
this plus icon has a bunch of other
things such as agent mode, which allows
CHB to control certain websites and do
some small actions for you. Deep
research. This is very good for photo
research on topics. It can browse like
20, 30 different websites and create a
detailed report. Now, here are some more
pro tips for you. Tell it add to memory
when you want CHB to remember something,
right? Maybe a city you live in or some
style of responding. Whatever you want
to remember across multiple
conversations, just say add to memory
and it will save it. Also, try to use
the projects feature on the left
sidebar. This is very good for managing
different areas of your life because you
can set a system prompt for each
project. So, here inside of JGBT, if you
click on the sidebar, you can see you
have a bunch of projects here and if you
just click on new project and give it a
name, give it a system prompt. That way
you don't have to repeat the same
prompts over and over. Also, if you are
a pro user, you can toggle the show
legacy models in the settings. That way,
you can access the older models that
were removed, right? So, right here, if
you click on your account and click on
settings, you should be able to see show
legacy models if you are a paying user.
And if you toggle that on in the model
selector, you can see all of the
previous models that otherwise were
removed and you cannot access them. All
right, let's check GPT5 Pro, which is
still running. That's very impressive.
And by the way, if you want unlimited
access to CH GBD5, you have to pay for
the $200 a month plan, which personally
I kind of disagree with that. So what we
did inside of Vectal, we added unlimited
GBD5 to everyone on Veectal Pro. So
while OpenAI is charging you $200 a
month to access unlimited GBD5, inside
of Veectal, you get unlimited GBD5 for
10 times less. Plus, you can also use
all the other cuttingedge AI models from
the other companies. So, if you want
access to unlimited GPT5, go to Vectori
and sign up. All right, so GPD5 Pro
finally finished running. It only took 6
minutes 13 seconds. I mean, this is a
powerful model, so it's expected to run
for a long time. And it did not end up
using canvas, so that is kind of
disappointing. So, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to copy all of this. Boom.
Copy. I'm going to switch to a new CHB
window. I'm going to manually trigger
canvas. I'm going to paste in all of the
code and I'm going to say visualize this
in canvas for me. Okay, so this uh
wasn't really optimal. It rewrote the
code, but let's run it. And there we go.
However, it says an error occurred.
We're trying to run 3D multi-object
canvas. So, while GBD5 is certainly
better than the previous version, GBD4,
it is still nowhere near AGI. And there
are actually much better AI models for
coding. So, if you want me to make a
video on that, showing how GBD5 compares
to cloth code, Grog 4 or Gemini 2.5 Pro,
comment below part two. If I see a lot
of comments that say parts two, I will
make this video comparing GBD5 to all of
the other alternatives specifically for
software development. With that being
said, thank you guys for watching and I
wish you a wonderful productive week.
See you.